<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>admin &#8211; Dextroid</title>
	<atom:link href="https://dextroid.in/blog/author/admin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://dextroid.in/blog</link>
	<description>Technology, Simplified!</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:18:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://dextroid.in/blog/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/cropped-mfavicon-32x32.png</url>
	<title>admin &#8211; Dextroid</title>
	<link>https://dextroid.in/blog</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Why Only The Camera Can See ‘Infrared Light’ Coming Out Of A Remote?</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/why-only-the-camera-can-see-infrared-light-coming-out-of-a-remote/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/why-only-the-camera-can-see-infrared-light-coming-out-of-a-remote/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=91</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You must have done this someday in your life, where you took your television remote and checked the infrared light coming out of it through a camera. You feel great when you do it for the first time, as it feels like some magic that you cannot see it with the naked eyes but the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-bqn68">You must have done this someday in your life, where you took your <em>television remote</em> and checked the <em>infrared light</em> coming out of it through a camera. You feel great when you do it for the first time, as it feels like some magic that you cannot see it with the naked eyes but the light is visible through the camera. Those who have not tried it yet, must try it right now and get the experience before reading any further as this post is about the reason behind it being visible only in the camera. Whenever we press the buttons of the remote, the <em>infrared light travels to the appliance from the remote</em> and that is how we control it.</p>



<p id="viewer-2jkff">In scientific words, the human eye sees the wavelengths between approximately <em>390 to 700nm</em>, and Infrared light has a range of around <em>700nm to 1mm</em>. The digital cameras can detect light <em>outside the visible spectrum</em> and that is why it can be seen in the camera. One of the Quora users wrote it to so that people can understand it easily, &#8220;Because the camera has a sensor that responds to IR as well as visible light. The <em>electrical signal from the IR light is converted back to visible light by the LEDs (or LCD) on the phone’s screen</em>. Since there is <em>no color that we sense as IR</em>, the camera designers just show IR as white. But the designers could have chosen a different color than white, maybe dark red- that might look better to us. Designers of thermal IR cameras do allow showing different intensities of IR as different colors.”</p>



<p id="viewer-2u5tl">You can even see the <em>infrared emitter</em> through the camera that is on the front of the television. The emitter is what <em>detects the infrared light passed from the remote</em> to the television, and works according to the controls given. Sunlight has <em>visible light, ultraviolet light, and infrared light</em> as well, so when we use the camera to see the sunlight we can feel the difference in the lights coming from the Sun. If you haven&#8217;t tried it yet, then do it now and let us know about your experience in the comments section below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/why-only-the-camera-can-see-infrared-light-coming-out-of-a-remote/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turn Your Selfie Into &#8216;Poem Portrait&#8217; With This Google AI Technology</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/turn-your-selfie-into-poem-portrait-with-this-google-ai-technology/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/turn-your-selfie-into-poem-portrait-with-this-google-ai-technology/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=88</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Artificial Intelligence is the future of the technological world, and we are already seeing the different aspects of it in our devices. It has evolved a lot through this decade, and even smartphones have the features and hardware that are dependent on AI. Earlier, it was limited to the science and technology related to the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-5bkvl">Artificial Intelligence is the future of the technological world, and we are already seeing the different aspects of it in our devices. It has evolved a lot through this decade, and even smartphones have the features and hardware that are dependent on AI. Earlier, it was limited to the science and technology related to the robotics area but with time every person in the world can now use artificial intelligence for various purposes. Now, <em>Google has come up with new development in AI technology with PoemPortrait</em>. The AI can be used to <em>create poem portraits with you entering a word of your choice</em>, as with that word the AI would generate the poem.</p>



<p id="viewer-3v5s4">So, the steps are that simple: take a selfie, and then give a word to the AI and the rest would be done with the technology. That one word would be expanded into a poem like the AI-driven phrase generators. Like if you give the word technology then it gives phrases like, <em>&#8220;The technology of those who have drawn our lives, was the first moon upon the waves.&#8221;</em> So, the AI gives a nice filter, as well as beautiful poetry on the picture. The text that gets generated on the face of the person would look like it is being projected there. You can access the web application with this link <a href="https://artsexperiments.withgoogle.com/poemportraits?_ga=2.225502810.1741562607.1556788599-1908717303.1556788599" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">PoemPortraits</a>, and then you will read something like “An experiment at the boundaries of AI and human collaboration. Donate a word to become part of an ever-evolving collective poem and create your own POEMPORTRAIT.”</p>



<p id="viewer-8m2ej">Then you have to <em>click Begin, enter a word, and click donate</em>, in the next picture you have to <em>click a selfie, and voila you have your picture with the poetry ready.</em> The picture really becomes better with the filter, and the poem and this AI is all about that only. The AI has been trained for nineteenth-century poetry, and the pictures would be a recreation of all the images that have been from DevianArt circa 2002. We can see <em>POEMPORTRAITS by Es Devlin and Google Arts &amp; Culture</em> written on all of the images that get generated through the AI. The original lines of poetry are generated through AI that gives a meaningful sentence, and that is a really fascinating thing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/turn-your-selfie-into-poem-portrait-with-this-google-ai-technology/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DONT GET BLOCKED ON WHATSAPP: Guidelines to broadcast messages to WhatsApp</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/dont-get-blocked-on-whatsapp-guidelines-to-broadcast-messages-to-whatsapp/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/dont-get-blocked-on-whatsapp-guidelines-to-broadcast-messages-to-whatsapp/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=85</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Business messaging is now a vital and esteemed aspect of the customer journey as more than one out of two customers are preferring businesses to use modern channels to communicate with them, with 53% of customers are interested to engage with a business where they can message directly. Considering the fact, many businesses are starting [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-erc2s">Business messaging is now a vital and esteemed aspect of the customer journey as more than one out of two customers are preferring businesses to use modern channels to communicate with them, with 53% of customers are interested to engage with a business where they can message directly. Considering the fact, many businesses are starting to adapt to WhatsApp as a channel for customer communication.</p>



<p id="viewer-d7d0p">Regardless of whether your WhatsApp account is blocked by a customer or by WhatsApp itself, the reasons are regularly down to either breaking WhatsApp&#8217;s terms of service or a complaint of customer lead by poor user experience. Whatever the reason, getting blocked on WhatsApp will be a nightmare for any business.</p>



<p id="viewer-ecmr6">Following the mentioned guidelines will ensure your WhatsApp account will not get blocked.</p>



<p id="viewer-4i3eg"><strong>Let customers save your WhatsApp number</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-bs1gv">In the event when customers are saving your business/individual WhatsApp number in their telephone contacts at that point blocking chances are significantly less. So consistently urge customers to save your WhatsApp number.</p>



<p id="viewer-4vouf"><strong>OPT-IN</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-9rbch">You should send messages only to customers who have OPT-IN to get business messages from your WhatsApp number. It will be ideal for a business to develop a subscription list of OPT-IN by communicating through email or text messages and requesting them to OPT-IN. Businesses should also give an option to OPT-OUT from messaging list to customers if they feel like to unsubscribe from the list by using keywords like &#8220;UNSUB&#8221; &#8220;OPTOUT&#8221; &#8220;STOP&#8221; etc.</p>



<p id="viewer-cr54u"><strong>NO SPAMMING</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-8gqot">Do not send irrelevant and frequent messages to your customers just to increase sale and also, avoid sending messages between 9 pm to 9 am. This can irritate customers and can lead to spam reporting to WhatsApp and then blocking.</p>



<p id="viewer-da3kb"><strong>2-way Interactions</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-dq55e">The easiest way to avoid number blocking on WhatsApp by customers is through interactions. A business should always put the best efforts to develop a 2-way communication channel with its subscriber&#8217;s list, particularly if the beneficiary answers back to your message or if the discussion started by the customer.</p>



<p id="viewer-beu9r"><strong>Integrate WhatsApp business account</strong></p>



<p id="viewer-8mdvn">A business should migrate from a personal WhatsApp account and should integrate WhatsApp Business account as a channel for communication with its customers as a blocking algorithm of WhatsApp business is different from WhatsApp personal account.</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote" id="viewer-5t12f"><p>Please note WhatsApp blocking algorithm get updated time to time and so practices mentioned in this article explains only the best practice to avoid blocking. SocialEpoch (<a href="http://www.wascrm.com/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"><u>www.wascrm.com</u></a>) and its services do not have any control on WhatsApp algorithm and will make the best way to grow your business on WhatsApp.</p></blockquote>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/dont-get-blocked-on-whatsapp-guidelines-to-broadcast-messages-to-whatsapp/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Instantly Check Out Who Is &#8216;Not Following You Back&#8217; On Instagram</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/instantly-check-out-who-is-not-following-you-back-on-instagram/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/instantly-check-out-who-is-not-following-you-back-on-instagram/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=82</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You get a notification that @anonymous followed you, you follow them back if you aren’t already following them. Then one day you check out your followers&#8217; list and find out that the account is nowhere there. Have you ever experienced this? Well, don’t think that it happened mistakenly as this is a trick that many [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-2r25l">You get a notification that <em>@anonymous</em> followed you, you follow them back if you aren’t already following them. Then one day you check out your followers&#8217; list and find out that the account is nowhere there. Have you ever experienced this? Well, don’t think that it happened mistakenly as this is a trick that many of the people use to gain a lot of followers while keeping the following list as less as possible. It is not that easy to check this for everyone you are following, and Instagram doesn’t even show on the profile of someone whether they are following you or not.</p>



<p id="viewer-1faln">So what should you do to check the people who are not following you back? There are applications that you can use to get the whole list at once, and makes it easy for us to<em> track and unfollow the unfollowers</em>. One of the best apps for that is <em><strong>Unfollow for Instagram &#8211; Non followers &amp; Fans</strong></em> and it is available for free in the play store. More features available in the application are</p>



<p id="viewer-fq3mh"><em>• Check mutual followers</em> <em>• Check fans, people who follow you without you following them</em> <em>• Check non-followers, people who aren’t following you back</em> <em>• Make a white list of people you don’t want to follow</em> <em>• Follow followers of a specific account</em></p>



<p id="viewer-cjmh8">You can see all of the accounts in a list, and you can follow or unfollow them from there only with a tap of a button. For logging in you will have to enter the credentials of your Instagram account, and you are all done after that. The application is really easy to use, can be used to unfollow or follow multiple accounts and you can also have multiple Instagram accounts logged in. If you haven’t tried it yet, then install it and check out your unfollowers right now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/instantly-check-out-who-is-not-following-you-back-on-instagram/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>If You Think Nothing Is Impossible, Then Try Naming The &#8216;New Folder&#8217; With These Terms</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/if-you-think-nothing-is-impossible-then-try-naming-the-new-folder-with-these-terms/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/if-you-think-nothing-is-impossible-then-try-naming-the-new-folder-with-these-terms/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=79</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[You might have been doing a lot of things in your computer system, and then there are simple things like creating a new folder. Well, creating the folder is quite easy but when it comes to naming it then you might not be able to give any name you want. There are some exceptions, and [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-8bvlg">You might have been doing a lot of things in your computer system, and then there are simple things like creating a new folder. Well, creating the folder is quite easy but when it comes to naming it then you might not be able to give any name you want. There are some exceptions, and we are not even talking about the various symbols that are restricted but the alphabetical and numerical terms only. The terms that you cannot use as the name of a folder are <em>CON, PRN, AUX, NUL, COM1, COM2, COM3, COM4, COM5, COM6, COM7, COM8, COM9, LPT1, LPT2, LPT3, LPT4, LPT5, LPT6, LPT7, LPT8, and LPT9</em>.</p>



<p id="viewer-2rnf0">If you want to try then just right-click on your desktop, create a new folder and then name it as any of the terms above and you will be prompted with <em>“The specified device name is invalid.”</em> You can even try renaming any of the files, or folders with those names and you will not be able to succeed in that too. It’s not like you can add an extension to the term and use it as the name. You cannot name CON.jpg either, so it is a total no-no for you when it comes to this. The reason behind this is that those <em>keywords have been kept reserved</em> for the tasks for the operating system. The system itself creates folders with these words for storing information of different functions like printing, and more.</p>



<p id="viewer-1r264">So, a file or folder with the same name would probably confuse the system is functioning in the correct way. That’s the reason it does not allow the user to create a file and folder with these words. But if you are much stubborn about the words, then there are two ways to use the same words for naming a file or folder. The first way is that you can just type the same name and then <em>press and hold the ALT key and type 255</em>, which will give an invisible character after it, and just <em>press enter</em>. With this ALT + 255 you can even have blank named folders and files. The other way is using the command line, just use md C:\Users\Admin\Desktop\con\ ( <em>should be the absolute URL of the location of your system </em>), and press enter. So, it is possible but if you have no idea about it then you might remain stunned for a while because of this.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/if-you-think-nothing-is-impossible-then-try-naming-the-new-folder-with-these-terms/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Can Search On Google Using &#8216;Your Handwriting&#8217; With This Simple Method</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/you-can-search-on-google-using-your-handwriting-with-this-simple-method/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/you-can-search-on-google-using-your-handwriting-with-this-simple-method/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=76</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Everyone uses Google as it is the most powerful search engine for a long time, and the company keeps coming up with a lot of features that make the search experience better and easy. We already know about the voice search and the gesture support that comes up with the Gboard – the Google Keyboard [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-bjm38">Everyone uses Google as it is the most powerful search engine for a long time, and the company keeps coming up with a lot of features that make the search experience better and easy. We already know about the voice search and the gesture support that comes up with the Gboard – the Google Keyboard which can be used to type with the gestures. But many of the users do not about the hidden feature of Google Search with which <em>you can use your handwriting to type the words that you want to search.</em> The method is really easy and does not need any kind of extra application or features on the smartphone.</p>



<p id="viewer-al8cd">The feature is there for a long time, but not many of us know about it. Google Handwriting allows you to write out what you are searching for rather than typing with the keyboard. The coolest thing about the search is that it is <em>really responsive and you can write anywhere on the screen</em>. In the Gboard you have written it at a particular space but here <em>the whole screen is yours and you can do the gesturing anywhere you want.</em> But this feature comes disabled so you need to enable it first to use it, and for that, you need to follow these steps.</p>



<p id="viewer-ea3uf">Open your browser in the smartphone, and go to the Google Homepage, then tap in <em>Setting &gt; Search Setting &gt; Enable the Handwrite</em> mode. That’s it, you can now search for anything on the internet with a few gestures. Below the page, you can see the <em>space button and backspace to use it while writing the words</em>. You can even write the letter above each other, and it will break it up into the characters. To disable you can go the same setting, and <em>to turn it off at that particular moment you can tap on the G icon at the lower left side of the screen.</em> If you haven’t tried it yet, then give it a go and let us know in the comments section below that whether you are going to use it or not.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/you-can-search-on-google-using-your-handwriting-with-this-simple-method/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Dvorak Layout Makes Us Type Faster With More Accuracy, Then Why Is &#8216;QWERTY&#8217; Used Everywhere?</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/dvorak-layout-makes-us-type-faster-with-more-accuracy-then-why-is-qwerty-used-everywhere/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/dvorak-layout-makes-us-type-faster-with-more-accuracy-then-why-is-qwerty-used-everywhere/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:11:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=73</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The modern age of typing came with the invention of typewriters, but initially, the buttons of the typewriter were arranged in an alphabetical manner. But there was a problem with the typewriters that when typing fast the typebars used to get stuck and jammed as all of it had to hit at the same place. [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-bt1g2">The modern age of typing came with the invention of typewriters, but initially, the buttons of the typewriter were arranged in an <em>alphabetical manner</em>. But there was a problem with the typewriters that <em>when typing fast the typebars used to get stuck and jammed</em> as all of it had to hit at the same place. Then the person typing had to unjam it, and that was really tiring. The typewriter got the <em>QWERTY layout in the year 1867 by Christopher Latham Sholes</em> just to get rid of that problem. In this layout, the most commonly used characters were placed far from each other, which lessened the jams and increased the typing speed.</p>



<p id="viewer-4n0qp">Also, the <em>shift key</em> was introduced later into the typewriters to <em>increase the number of symbols</em>, and bring both the alphabetical cases. Then the <em>Dvorak layout was introduced in the year 1936 by Auguste Dvorak</em> and obviously he named it after himself. Dvorak <em>minimized the errors and the unnecessary finger movements</em> that led them to type <em>74 percent faster and is 68% more accurate</em>. With an average of 52 hours of training, the typists gained this speed, and that is why it is still debated that why is Dvorak not the preferred one. Well, the reason is not that reasonable but it is just because QWERTY was already a lot popular.</p>



<p id="viewer-d9llt">Everyone was used to typing with the QWERTY layout, and that made Dvorak fall behind. But still, some people prefer using it as it is quite easy to <em>take out and replace the keys and then change it to the Dvorak layout in the keyboard settings</em>. The option of changing the layout to Dvorak comes in all of the operating systems except for iOS. But most of the games and software are built for the QWERTY layout and that can create some problems. Even if you are used to the QWERTY layout, you should give Dvorak a try and let us know in the comments section about the experience.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/dvorak-layout-makes-us-type-faster-with-more-accuracy-then-why-is-qwerty-used-everywhere/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>This is the quickest way to download YouTube videos</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/this-is-the-quickest-way-to-download-youtube-videos/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/this-is-the-quickest-way-to-download-youtube-videos/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=70</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We all use YouTube on a daily basis, and we wish to keep some of its content on our device to watch it over and over again. Many people want to download it so that they do not have to suffer the buffer or want to watch it whenever and wherever they want. While there [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-es4u7">We all use YouTube on a daily basis, and we wish to keep some of its content on our device to watch it over and over again. Many people want to download it so that they do not have to <em>suffer the buffer or want to watch it whenever and wherever they want</em>. While there are many ways like having a <em>YouTube downloader </em>software, or <em>various online sites</em> that let you get the video in different qualities using the URL. But then these sites, or software take a bit of your time as you have to <em>copy the link of the video, paste it there and then choose the quality</em> and download it.</p>



<p id="viewer-amekc">The simplest, and the quickest way is to add two characters to the URL of the YouTube video, and you will be redirected to the page from where you can download the video in different qualities and formats. The video can be downloaded from the lowest 3gp to Full HD without any trouble. The characters that you need to add to the URL are <em>‘ss’</em> without the inverted commas. For example, if the link is <em>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0jNvJU52LvU then you just have to add ‘ss’ after ‘www.’ like https://www./<strong>ss</strong>youtube.com/watch?v=0jNvJU52LvU then</em> press enter and you will be redirected to the site with all the options.</p>



<p id="viewer-9peu0">This is the easiest way, and you can save a lot of time with this. The video will be downloaded using the <em>download manager of the browser</em>, and if there is a download accelerator software then that will be used. So, from now you <em>do not need to suffer the buffer for your favorite videos and you can also keep a good collection of videos in your device</em> using this quick method. What are you waiting for? Go give it a try, and let us know in the comments section below that how much did you like it.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/this-is-the-quickest-way-to-download-youtube-videos/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Slow phone? Here is what you need to do instead of just clearing the cache</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/slow-phone-here-is-what-you-need-to-do-instead-of-just-clearing-the-cache/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/slow-phone-here-is-what-you-need-to-do-instead-of-just-clearing-the-cache/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=67</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What is more frustrating than buying a phone with great specifications, and then seeing it hang after some use? Well, nowadays phones that are coming up are efficient enough and do not hang even after some hefty use but there are still a few phones in the market or at your home that hangs after [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-n4pt">What is more frustrating than buying a phone with <em>great specifications</em>, and then seeing it hang after some use? Well, nowadays phones that are coming up are efficient enough and do not hang even after some hefty use but there are still a <em>few phones in the market or at your home that hangs after some use</em> and that is really frustrating. There are ways that you already know like <em>clearing the cache</em> of the applications or <em>clearing the data</em> but these are just the basic methods that everyone is aware of. These actions do fasten up the speed of the phone, but not up to the level where there is no lag at all. Every phone works smoothly when we buy it, but with time it starts getting slower.</p>



<p id="viewer-au01b">So, do clear the cache of all the applications from the storage as it is the most basic method to start speeding up the process. The other thing that will make your phone run faster is <em>disabling the animations</em> of the phone. The fluid feel of the phone comes with those transitions but eats up a lot of memory too, and all we need is to give the memory some space to work well. To do that <em>go to settings, then about the phone, tap the build number seven times to bring the developer options</em>. In the developer, options <em>tap window animation scale and change it to animation off.</em></p>



<p id="viewer-53ktl">Do the same with the <em>transition animation scale, animator duration scale</em> and that is all. After finishing the steps, you will get no transitions but the hanging problem would be a lot less with it turned off. Another thing that you need to do is to uninstall the apps that are of no use to you, and also <em>disable the bloat-wares</em> that are the pre-installed apps so that it doesn’t eat up the RAM in the background. Also, <em>on the home screen of the phone keep as fewer apps and widgets as possible</em>. These are the few steps that would fasten up the speed of your phone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/slow-phone-here-is-what-you-need-to-do-instead-of-just-clearing-the-cache/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>You see &#8216;I’m Feeling Lucky&#8217; on Google Search every day, but do you ever use it?</title>
		<link>https://dextroid.in/blog/you-see-im-feeling-lucky-on-google-search-every-day-but-do-you-ever-use-it/</link>
					<comments>https://dextroid.in/blog/you-see-im-feeling-lucky-on-google-search-every-day-but-do-you-ever-use-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 20:06:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://dextroid.in/blog/?p=64</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The homepage of Google Search is one of the cleanest websites with no advertisements or extra things that eat up the screen space. The company has only kept the things that are the most important, and that is how you know that if “I’m feeling lucky”wasn’t important then it would not have been there. It [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p id="viewer-7pb5g">The homepage of Google Search is one of the cleanest websites with no advertisements or extra things that eat up the screen space. The company has only kept the things that are the most important, and that is how you know that if <em><strong>“I’m feeling lucky”</strong></em>wasn’t important then it would not have been there. It appears next to the Google Search button but it is something that we never see, or maybe we are so much used to seeing that button that it doesn’t even come to our mind to check it out. The <em>button has been there since 1998 when Google was founded</em>, and it has been there throughout the years.</p>



<p id="viewer-amtag">Most of the people think that it is just a useless thing that Google is offering, but what they don’t know is that it can be a lot useful for you. Pressing enter gets you to the Google results page directly, so that is another reason for we overlooking the button residing next to it. Now let us come to the use of that button as from the phrase it is quite unclear that what it actually offers. <em>If you write nothing and click on the button then you will be taken to the Google Doodles page</em> where you can see all of the doodles that Google has ever come up with. So, the next time when you have to check out the different doodles without searching for anything, you know where to click.</p>



<p id="viewer-32sd4">When you type something, and then click on the <em>‘I’m feeling lucky’</em> button then it will <em>directly open the first ranked page</em> for the phrase and most of the time that is helpful. It <em>saves a few clicks, and a few seconds of yours</em> and this also feels a bit technically advanced feature. If you have to check out the different results then this isn’t helpful, but if you want something that you are sure of would be the first result then it is a pro thing to do. If you have to watch the video song Hello by Adele, then you just have to <em>type ‘hello’ and click on the button and you would be redirected to the YouTube page</em>. If you search for Facebook using that button, then the homepage of Facebook would open directly and so on. Do give it a try the next time you open Google and tell us your experience in the comments section below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://dextroid.in/blog/you-see-im-feeling-lucky-on-google-search-every-day-but-do-you-ever-use-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
